Orchestration:
Docker Swarm:

*Scale containers.
*Upgrade the srvice with Zero down time.
*manage /recreate containers if it crashes or fails.
*manage Containers on VM's and nodes.

Benifits
-------
➤ Task Scheduling :
➤ Load Balancing :
➤ Rolling Updates :
➤ Security :

➤ Docker Swarm :
➤ Docker Swarm is a clustering and scheduling tool
for Docker containers.
➤ Swarm is Docker’s native support for orchestrating clusters of
Docker engines.
➤ Orchestration : Define nodes. Define services. Set how many
nodes you want to run and where, and you’re done.
➤ At a high level, Swarm takes multiple Docker Engines running
on different hosts and lets you use them together.
➤ Docker Swarm : Docker Swarm have Two Type of Nodes
Master(Manager) and Worker.
➤ Every swarm starts out with one manager node designated as
the leader.
➤ Swarm is highly available thanks to its implementation of the
Raft algorithm.
➤ Raft Algo : The leader node is constantly checking in with its
fellow manager nodes and syncing their states.

-------------------
Terminology:

➤ Docker Swarm : The cluster management and orchestration
features embedded in the Docker Engine are built
using swarmkit.
➤ A swarm consists of multiple Docker hosts which run
in swarm mode and act as managers (to manage membership
and delegation) and workers (which run swarm services).
➤ Host : Docker host can be a manager, a worker, or perform both
roles.
➤ Service : When you create a service, you define its optimal state
(number of replicas, network and storage resources available to
it, ports the service exposes to the outside world, and more).
➤ Docker Swarm : Docker Swarm maintains the Service Desired
State. For instance, if a worker node becomes unavailable,
Docker schedules that node’s tasks on other nodes.
➤ Task : Task is a running container which is part of a swarm
service and managed by a swarm manager.
➤ Nodes : A node is an instance of the Docker engine participating in
the swarm.
➤ You can run one or more nodes on a single physical computer or
cloud server, but production swarm deployments typically include
Docker nodes distributed across multiple physical and cloud
machines.
➤ To deploy your application to a swarm, you submit a service
definition to a manager node. The manager node dispatches units of
work called tasks to worker nodes.
➤ Manager nodes also perform the orchestration and cluster
management functions required to maintain the desired state of the
swarm. Manager nodes elect a single leader to conduct orchestration
tasks.
➤ Worker nodes receive and execute tasks dispatched from
manager nodes.
➤ Service : A service is the definition of the tasks to execute on
the manager or worker nodes.
➤ When you create a service, you specify which container image
to use and which commands to execute inside running
containers.
➤ Task : A task carries a Docker container and the commands
to run inside the container.
➤ Once a task is assigned to a node, it cannot move to another
node. It can only run on the assigned node or fail.
➤ Load Balancing : Swarm manager uses ingress load
balancing to expose the services you want to make available
externally to the swarm.
➤ External components, such as cloud load balancers, can access
the service on the PublishedPort of any node in the cluster
whether or not the node is currently running the task for the
service. All nodes in the swarm route ingress connections to a
running task instance.
_-----------------------------------------------------------------------

➤ Initialize Docker Swarm
-->docker swarm init
-->docker swarm init --advertise-addr 192.168.99.100
➤ Docker Swarm Commands
➤ Docker Service Commands
➤ Create Docker Service
-->docker service create <image>
➤ List all running services in Docker Host
-->docker service ls 
➤ Start some Services on Docker Swarm Host
➤ Identify running Container for the Service
-->docker service ps <service_name>
➤ Scale Up the services
-->docker service update <service_name> - -replicas <Number
of Services>
➤ Difference in Docker Update and Docker Service Update
➤ Verify Auto Scale with Swarm 

-----------------------------------------------------------------------

➤ Create Docker Swarm Cluster.
➤ play-with-docker.com
➤ Docker Machine + Virtual Box
➤ Digital Ocean + Docker Install
➤ RollOut machine on Cloud like AWS, Google, Azure, DO etc.
➤ Create Docker Swarm Cluster.
➤ play-with-docker.com
➤ Docker Machine + Virtual Box
➤ Digital Ocean + Docker Install
➤ RollOut machine on Cloud like AWS, Google, Azure, DO etc.
➤ Verify Which Node is running, which containers

