Kubernetes
==============================================================

*Kubernetes is Open Source Orchestration system for Docker Containers.
*Kubernetes Implemented by Google.
*Kubernetes is a platform that eliminates the manual processes involved in deploying containerised applications.
*Kubernetes used to manage the State of Containers.
	-->Start Containers on Specific Nodes.
	-->Restart Containers when gets Killed.
	-->Move containers one Node to Another.

Challenges without Orchestration:
++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
*Increase the Human Cost of Running Service
*Increase the Bills from Cloud Service Provider
*Increase Complexity of Infrastructure
*Scaling was very Difficult
*Setting Up Services Manually
*Manual Fix if any Node is Crashed

Features of Kubernetes:
++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

-->Automated Scheduling : Kubernetes provides advanced scheduler to launch container on cluster nodes based on their resource requirements and other constraints.
-->Healing Capabilities: Kubernetes allows to replaces and reschedules containers when nodes die. Kubernetes doesn’t allow Containers to use, until they get ready.
-->Auto Upgrade and RollBack : Kubernetes rolls out changes to the application or its configuration.Monitoring Application ensure that Kubernetes doesn’t kill all Instance at that time.If something goes wrong, with Kubernetes you can rollback the change.
-->Horizontal Scaling : Kubernetes can scale up and scale down the application as per the requirements with a simple command, using a UI, or automatically based on CPU usage.
-->Storage Orchestration : With Kubernetes, you can mount the storage system of your choice. You can either opt for local storage, or choose a public cloud provider.
-->Secret & Configuration Management : Kubernetes can help you deploy and update secrets and application configuration without rebuilding your image and without exposing secrets in your stack configuration.
-->You can Run Kubernetes Anywhere:
On-Premise(Own DataCenter)
Public Cloud(Google, AWS, Azure, DigitalOcean…)
Hybrid Cloud
